vioc.com 2017-06-15

# Valvoline Instant Oil Change

Thank you for your trust in Valvoline Instant Oil Change, and for taking the time to read our Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy tells you how we protect the privacy of your personal information that you may provide to us.

Time-It Lube is now part of Valvoline Instant Oil Change.  

We have organized our web sites so that you will not be required to identify yourself or reveal any personal Information in order to view our web sites. At times, we may ask you to provide information about yourself or your company in order to better serve you. If you choose to provide this personally identifiable information, we will use it in accordance with this Privacy Statement. By entering this web site, you are consenting to the terms of this Privacy Statement. This Privacy Statement only applies to data collected on the Valvoline Instant Oil Change web site (www.vioc.com). Other individual web sites of Valvoline or Ashland Inc. (collectively "Ashland"), including Valvoline.com, may have privacy statements tailored specifically for activity on those web sites and the terms of those privacy statements may differ from this Privacy Statement.

### Purpose of Privacy Policy

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to answer some of the questions that you may have about what we do with the personally identifiable information that we may collect from our web site. We want you to know that your personally identifiable information will be protected, who we may share it with, and for what purposes.

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to update this Privacy Statement at any time without notice to you. The most current version of the Privacy Statement can be reviewed by clicking on the "Privacy Policy" hypertext link located at the bottom of the web pages on this web site. Your use of this web site may also be subject to additional terms as outlined in the Terms of Use and elsewhere on this web site.

### What Information Do We Collect and How Do We Use It

We understand that you expect to learn about our company when you visit this web site. Similarly, we hope to learn about your needs as a current or potential customer or shareholder through your visits to this web site. On some of our web pages, you may be able to ask questions, register to receive information, enter sweepstakes or enter information about your vehicle.

### Collection of Personal Information

Many of our web pages do not require any form of registration or identification. However, on some of our web pages you may be able to ask questions and register to receive information or offers. On these pages we will ask you for the personal information necessary for us to respond to you, such as your name, mailing address, electronic mail address, and telephone number. If you opt to not provide us with personal information you can still access our web sites; however you may be unable to participate in certain promotions, receive product information offered through Ashland's web sites, responses to requests for materials or information, or interactive advertisements.

Data Integrity

We take reasonable steps to ensure that personally identifiable data collected is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete and current. We limit the collection and processing of the personally identifiable information which you provide to us to only what is necessary to fulfill the purpose.

Consent to Provide Your Information

We request your permission to collect your personally identifiable information when you seek to register for any of our programs or services. In doing so, we also explain the purpose for the collection of your personal information and how we plan to use it. We also offer you the option to discontinue your consent ("opting out" or "unsubscribing") if you later decide that you no longer want to participate in a program or service. If we wish to use this information for purposes that differ from those for which the data was initially collected, we will first request your permission to do so.

Aggregate and Statistical Data

When you visit our web sites we do not collect any personally identifiable information about you without your express permission. However, we may collect certain aggregate data called web log information (such as your web browser, operating system, pages visited, etc.) and use cookies when you visit many of our web pages. For instance, when you visit one of our web sites, our web server will automatically recognize some non-personal information, including but not limited to the date and time you visited our site, the pages you visited, the referrer (the website you came from), the type of browser you are using (e.g., Chrome, Internet Explorer, Safari), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows 8 or Mac OS), the type of device you are using (e.g., Computer, Smartphone, Tablet) and the domain name and address of your Internet service provider (e.g., AOL, Time Warner Cable). This type of information allows us to evaluate customer interest in our web sites and perform other market research activities, such as surveying browsing habits on our sites. It also allows us to monitor traffic to our web sites.

We also contract with third parties to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet by utilizing cookies, pixel tags, or the Google Display Network which can include the use of remarketing data collected in Google Analytics™. These ads are served by collecting anonymous information about your visits to our website. The third parties may use this information to deliver you content while visiting other websites to encourage you to revisit our website. The data collected is anonymous, and no personally-identifiable information will be stored or shared. To opt-out of this form of advertising from Google please click [here](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCgn91c3egibiLjseVvqk2mibjHsKW-Pco3Pu_qsKaHNEhaHj71flSAmP2AJxbCelp2hKyqmakg8rUjC1hDZ-wz1GKlmCrJUTZhfI_BELfeZokMC_qTuiVAuDVUnEnG8CqmzDsYOsnEkZfVIwB6ul6dD655q26W0S3bw2NV0qSh6ShdKVLcnWzwXZjH67AU-spo-wzPnAzdq5cxohvtG25NKgKD1uilYa9Qku8cKWULwcx--BzUHJ_dyiR6bs2qt5uGkepqR) to manage your Google ad settings and [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to manage the data that can be collected in Google Analytics. To learn more, or to opt-out of receiving online display advertisements tailored to your interests by our other third party partners, visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices).  

Neither our cookies nor web beacons nor web log information collects any personal information, such as your name, email address, or any other personally identifiable information.

In some cases we may also collect information about you that you voluntarily submit, such as general statistical information like age, gender, household size, zip/postal code, preferences and interests, which, when submitted individually, is not personally identifiable.

Cookies and Web Beacons

When you view one of our web sites or interactive advertisements, we may collect some non-personal information about you. The collection of this non personal information is done either through the "cookie" technology or with "web beacons" (also called "single-pixel gif" or "web pings"). Neither our cookies nor web beacons nor web log information collects any personal information.

a) Cookies

When you view one of our web sites or interactive advertisements, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a small text file, also called a "cookie". Cookies help us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites.  We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests.  To opt out of these ads, please click here.   Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Ashland does not collect personal information automatically, but we may combine non-personal information collected automatically (e.g., through cookies) with your previously submitted personal information. When this non-personal information is collected and combined with your submitted information we will treat the combined information as personal information. Our cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive, cannot read cookie files created by other web sites and cannot track any personal information about you. If you erase or reject a cookie, you may still use this web site.

b) Web Beacons

Web beacons are site instrumentation that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. When you ask us to send you information on a promotion or a newsletter, we may use web beacons to establish how many of the emails are actually opened. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.

If you would like more information about web beacons and cookies associated with on-line advertising or how to opt out of third party collection of information, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative web site, an independent web site not sponsored by or affiliated with Ashland Inc.

What Do We Do With Your Information

We will use the information that you provide us to better understand your needs and to provide you with better products and services. At the most basic level, we will use information you provide to communicate with you, to update you on our products and services, provide special offers, and to personalize our web sites for you. Web logs may be used if necessary to help identify any person attempting to break into or damage our web site. We may share web log information as well as any associated personally identifiable information with law enforcement agencies if we believe that we have evidence of a violation of computer security or related laws.

Periodically, we may survey you about your use of products for other market research or to provide you with marketing information we think will be useful to you. Of course, it is not required that you participate in these surveys or accept this marketing information to continue to use our web sites or continue to receive communications from us.

Will My Information Be Sold to Third Parties

No. Except as specifically provided for in this policy, we will not sell or share the personal information which you give to us to unaffiliated third parties, such as marketers, for their own separate use unless we have obtained your explicit opt-in consent to do so. We may make your provided personal information (such as name, mailing addresses and email addresses) accessible to our business partners, vendors, contractors or partners in connection with services that these individuals or entities perform for or with Ashland, such as companies we retain to fulfill requests for information or provide assistance to us on specific programs or projects; and non-personal information (such as vehicle information) with vendors, contractors, and other third parties. These vendors, contractors or partners are restricted by law and/or contract from using this data in any way other than to provide services for Ashland, and they may not share or resell this data. The services they provide for Ashland include, among other things, mailing product samples, or contacting the winners of Ashland contests.

There may also be instances where we may be required to share your information with third-parties who have not been retained by us (directly or indirectly) and Ashland reserves the right to share the information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law. For example, we may be required to do so because of an applicable law, court order or governmental regulation, or if such disclosure is otherwise necessary in support of any criminal or other legal investigation or proceeding in the United States or abroad. Many entities receiving personally identifiable information under these conditions have privacy requirements that apply to their handling of your information.

Personal information collected from you may also be transferred to a third party in the event that the business of this site or a part of it and the customer data connected with it is sold, assigned or transferred, in which case we would require the buyer, assignee or transferee to treat your information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

Links to Other Sites

This Privacy Statement applies only to this web site and not to other Ashland web sites or third party web sites. We may provide links to other web sites which we believe may be of interest to our visitors. We aim to ensure that such web sites are of a high standard. However, due to the nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee the privacy standards of web sites to which we link or be responsible for the contents of sites other than this one. This Privacy Statement is not intended to be applicable to any linked, non-Ashland site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements for all linked websites.

Privacy and Protection of Children

This web site is not designed for, or directed to, children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect, use or disclose personally identifiable information from a minor under the age of 13. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 provide personally identifiable information to us we will immediately remove that child and delete all personal information provided by the child from our records. We encourage parents to take an active role in their children’s online activities and to talk with their children about disclosing personally identifiable information to web sites.

Data Security

Ashland is committed to keeping the data you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. We use appropriate technical, administrative and physical safeguards to protect data that pertains to you. Of course, no organization can guarantee the absolute security of personal information. You should keep in mind that Internet transmissions, particularly email transmissions, are never 100% secure or error-free. Accordingly, we caution you to guard your own computer and password against unauthorized access by others. Vendors, contractors, or partners of Ashland who have access to your personal information in connection with providing services for Ashland are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Ashland. No one at Ashland, or its various business units, has access to your password or credit card information at any point as we use secure connections to fully encrypt this data on our web sites to protect it during its transmission.

Referrals

Occasionally, visitors will have the opportunity to forward product sampling opportunities or other information on the web site to friends/relatives or to send messages from our web sites or interactive advertisements to friends/relatives. The personal referral information you provide to facilitate this communication is used on a one-time basis and is not further used by Ashland to re-contact referred individuals, except in circumstances where we obtain consent from the people you have referred to receive communications from us. We may also retain such information for analysis to better serve our customers.

Photo Policy

We appreciate your participation in Valvoline Instant Oil Change’s social media channels (e.g. Facebook, Youtube, Twitter, etc). Please be aware of the following policies and guidelines:

  * All content (such as photos, text, images, videos) submitted or linked on this site or through social media is the sole responsibility of the person from which the content originated.

  * Valvoline Instant Oil Change reserves the right to remove any content that is deemed inappropriate, obscene, slanderous or malicious and may block users that contribute such content.

Remember that Valvoline Instant Oil Change’s website and social media channels are public forums. Any information you share may be viewed by others. By posting content to Valvoline Instant Oil Change’s website or social media, you grant Valvoline Instant Oil Change / Ashland permission to display, modify, reproduce and distribute this content without compensation.

By participating in Valvoline Instant Oil Change’s social media channels, you release Valvoline Instant Oil Change and Ashland from any liability associated therewith, and agree to recompense Valvoline Instant Oil Change against any damages, losses, liabilities, judgments, costs or expenses arising out of a claim by a third party relating to any posts you have made.

Updating Your Information

We encourage you to update the information that you provide to us, such as providing us with a new mailing or email address. This will help us continue to provide information to you that best meets your needs.

In addition, we comply with laws and regulations applicable to the right to amend your data in our files. These rights are limited in some ways. In addition, in order to protect your data from unauthorized access or alteration by third parties, all requests to update or access your information will be subject to verification of the identity of the requesting individual.

Accessing Your Information and Contacting Ashland

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, or if you have submitted or another person has submitted personally identifiable information about you through this web site, and you would like to have that information changed or deleted, please contact:

Ashland Communications and Corporate Affairs  
50 E. RiverCenter Blvd.  
P.O. Box 391  
Covington, KY 41012-0391 USA  
privacy@ashland.com

Voluntary Participation

Our sites allow you to choose to receive or stop receiving communications from us. To request removal from a mailing list, please visit the Contact Us page and send a message with your request.

Your Acceptance of Our Privacy Practices

By using this web site or any other Ashland web site or interactive banner ads, you signify your acceptance of this privacy statement, and you adhere to the terms and conditions posted on the web site.

If you do not agree with any of these terms in this privacy statement, please do not use this site or submit any personal information.

Please check back for updates to this privacy statement.

Updated Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement becomes effective January, 2015. Valvoline Instant Oil Change and Ashland may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy periodically.
